uptrends.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy | Uptrends

Uptrends LLC, its affiliated companies, and subsidiaries (“ **Uptrends** ,” “ **we** ," or “ **us** ”) are committed to the protecting the privacy of visitors of the Uptrends website(s), individuals who register to use the products and services, individuals who register to attend the Company’s corporate events, and business partners (“ **Customers** ”). This Privacy Notice (“ **Privacy Notice** ” or “ **Notice** ”) describes our privacy practices in relation to the use of Uptrends’ Websites (including any customer portal (" **Portal** ") or interactive customer website), software, services, solutions, tools, related applications, programs including attendance of corporate events and research and marketing activities offered by Uptrends (the “ **Services** ”), and your choices regarding use, access, and correction of personal data.

This Privacy Notice describes how we collect, use, disclose and otherwise process personal data collected related to our Services and otherwise in the course of our business activities, including the information practices of the websites(“ **Sites** ”) that link to this Privacy Notice .

This Privacy Notice does not apply to information collected about Uptrends employees, applicants, or other personnel.

The Uptrends Sites may contain links to other websites. These other websites’ privacy statements govern their information, practices, and/or content.

## About us

Uptrends provides its Services, which include web performance and server monitoring services, to business customers, directly, and through distributors, resellers, and managed service providers (MSPs).

## Customer owned data

As a provider of Services, we may receive, process, or store certain information including personal information on behalf of our Customers. Our Customers own all such information (“ **Customer Data** ”), and the Customers control the Customer Data with respect to EU data protection law. Customer Data may include information from the end points and other systems, tools, or devices that Customers manage or monitor using our Services, and end-user data related to individuals’ activities on Customer’s networks and systems. It may also include event logs, end-user information (such as IP address, email address, and computer name), and other data where relevant to a support or service request. Uptrends is a data processor for Customer Data. This means that Uptrends processes Customer Data on the basis of instructions from our Customers. If Uptrends receives a data subject request, we may point you in the direction of our Customer, as the Customer is the controller of the Customer Data.

## Personal data you provide to us

We collect Personal Data from you, such as first and last name, phone number, zip code, e-mail, professional title, company name, and password, when you purchase Products, register to receive information, or post a comment on our blog. In addition, we (or our third-party credit card or payment processor on our behalf) will collect Personal Data including your credit card number or account information when you purchase Products or services on our website. We also retain information on your behalf, such as the Personal Data described above and any correspondence or blog comments. If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail (e.g., in response to an employment opportunity posted on our website), we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply, and any information that you submit to us, such as a resume. When you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information such as your name, phone number, address, and e-mail address. When you post comments on our blog, the information contained in your posting will be stored on our servers and other users will be able to see it. To request removal of your personal information, contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. We also collect other types of Personal Data that you provide to us voluntarily, such as operating system and version, information about your application and operating environment, and other requested information if you contact us via e-mail regarding support for the Products). We may also collect Personal Data at other points in our website that state that Personal Data is being collected.

## Data relating to our customers and users of our sites

Uptrends collects information as part of its normal business operations and in the administration of its relationship with Customers, which may include personal data.

_Business contact and customer relationship management.  _ We collect and maintain information about our Customers, which may include company name, business contact name and title, phone number, email, and other contact details. We may also collect billing address, financial account, credit card information, order details, subscription and license information, and usage details. In addition, we collect user credential and profile data (name, contact, and authorized users) of Customer’s authorized users and account administrators.

_Data submitted on Sites._ ** _ _** To access or use certain portions of the Sites, to enjoy the full functionality of the Sites, or to conduct or seek to conduct business with us, you may be prompted to provide certain personal data to us in the following ways:

  * by filling in forms (for example, a “Contact Us” form) on our Sites or at a trade show or anywhere else we conduct business;
  * by downloading or accessing the Uptrends Services;
  * by downloading documentation from our Sites;
  * by subscribing to newsletters or other communications; or
  * by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail, or otherwise using our contact details.

Typically, the personal data you give us may include name, business affiliation, business address, telephone number, and email address, and any personal details needed to resolve any inquiries or complaints.

_Third parties._  We may also obtain personal data about Customers from third parties, such as LinkedIn and other publicly accessible sources.

_Customer support and service._ ** _ _** When Customers contact us for support or other customer service requests, we maintain support tickets and other records related to the requests including any information provided by Customers related to such support or service requests. We may also collect call recordings related to support and customer service-related calls.

_Usage details._  We collect information about Customers’ usage of our Services including IP address, Customer ID, email address, and other usage statistics. We do not collect usage details about Customers’ end users, except as necessary for support or to provide the Services requested by Customers (in which case we are a data processor of such data).

When you visit our Sites, our server automatically collects certain browser or device generated information, which may in some cases constitute personal data, including but not limited to:

  * your domain;
  * your IP address;
  * your date, time and duration of your visit;
  * your browser type;
  * your operating system;
  * your page visits;
  * information from third parties;
  * other information about your computer or device; or
  * Internet traffic.

_De-identified data._  We may de-identify and aggregate certain data we collect such that the data no longer identifies or can be linked to a particular customer or an individual data subject (“De-identified Data”) subject to the terms of any applicable customer agreements. We may use this data to improve our Services, analyze trends, publish market research, and for other marketing, research, or statistical purposes and may disclose such data to third parties for these specific purposes.

_Other data_. Uptrends collects, uses, and maintains certain data related to its business and the Services it provides to Customers, which is not personal data; this privacy notice does not restrict our use and processing of such data.

## Cookies

Our Sites use cookies. You can find more information about our use of cookies in our Cookie Policy located at https://www.uptrends.com/cookies.

## Use of Personal Data

The following is an overview of our purposes for using personal data that we process as a data controller. Additional details on how we process your personal data may be provided to you in a separate notice or contract.

For individuals in the European Union, we justify our processing (i.e. use) of your personal data on the following legal bases:

  * **Performance of contract:**  the processing is necessary to perform a contract with you or take steps to enter into a contract at your request;
  * **Compliance with law:**  the processing is necessary for us to comply with a relevant legal obligation (for example, laws which require us to collect tax information from customers, carry out checks on customers, or which compel us to disclose information to public authorities or regulators);
  * **Our legitimate interests:**  the processing is in our legitimate interests, subject to your interests and fundamental rights, and notably our legitimate interest in using applicable data to conduct and develop our business activities, such as developing and maintaining relationships with our customers (the majority of the processing covered by this notice is legitimate interest based); *
  * **Defend our rights:**  where the processing is necessary to the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims; or
  * **With your consent:**  you have consented to the processing (for example, where local law requires us to rely upon your prior consent for the purposes of direct marketing).

* In all cases where legitimate interests are relied upon as a lawful basis, we take steps to ensure that our legitimate interests are not outweighed by any prejudice to your rights and freedoms. This is achieved in a number of ways including through the application of principles of data minimization and security, by taking steps to ensure that personal data is only collected or otherwise obtained where it is relevant to the lawful business activities, and where using personal data is reasonably necessary for those activities.

## Disclosure of Personal Data

Uptrends is a global group of companies, and we may share personal data with our affiliated businesses as part of our business operations and administration of the Services. We may also appoint third-party service providers (who will operate under our instructions) to assist us in providing information, products, or services to you in conducting and managing our business or in managing and improving our Services or the Sites. Uptrends may share your personal data with these affiliates and third parties to perform services that Uptrends has engaged the third parties to perform on Uptrends' behalf subject to appropriate contractual restrictions and security measures, if we believe it is reasonably necessary to prevent harm or loss, or we believe that the disclosure will further an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activities.

Uptrends reserves the right to share any information that is not deemed personal data or is not otherwise subject to contractual restrictions.

If personal data is transferred outside the EU to other Uptrends group companies or third-party service providers, we will take steps to ensure that your personal data receives the same level of protection as if it remained within the EU. You have a right to obtain details of the mechanism under which your personal data is transferred outside of the EU by contacting us.

We contractually require agents, service providers, and affiliates who may process personal data related to the Services to provide the same level of protection for personal data as required under the GDPR (“ **Principles** ”). Uptrends does not transfer personal data to a third party for the third party’s own use, but only for Uptrends’ purposes as outlined above. Uptrends will remain liable under the Principles if one of its third-party processors processes personal data in a manner inconsistent with the Principles if we are responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

## Other Disclosures

_Law enforcement or national security_. In accordance with our legal obligations, we may also transfer Customer Data, subject to a lawful request, to public authorities for law enforcement or national security purposes.

_Additional disclosures_. We may also disclose Customer Data (including any personal data) where otherwise required by law.

_Business transfers._ ** _ _** We may share personal data with third parties in connection with the potential or actual sale of our company or any of our assets or those of any affiliated company in which case personal data held by us about our users may be one of the transferred assets.

_Just-in-time disclosures._  Additional disclosures or information about the processing of personal data related to specific websites, mobile applications, products, services, or programs may be provided to you. These may supplement and/or clarify Uptrends privacy practices in specific circumstances and provide you with additional choices as to how Uptrends may process your personal data.

## Children

The Sites, Services, and Portal are not for use by children under the age of 16 years, and Uptrends does not knowingly collect, store, share, or use the personal data of children under 16 years. If you are under the age of 16 years, please do not provide any personal data, even if prompted by the Sites to do so. If you are under the age of 16 years and you have provided personal data, please ask your parent(s) or guardian(s) to notify Uptrends, and Uptrends will delete all such personal data.

## Marketing

Where lawful to do so and subject to your consent where required, we may communicate with Customers (and related business contacts) about our Services. If you wish to unsubscribe from receiving marketing communications, please click on the link “unsubscribe” at the bottom of the email or contact us and provide us your email address so we can unsubscribe you, and we will stop sending you promotional emails.

## Security

Uptrends aims to safeguard and protect your personal data from unauthorized access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorized modification or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, and Uptrends uses and maintains certain reasonable processes, systems, and technologies to do so. However, you acknowledge that no environment is completely secure or error-free and that these processes, systems, and technologies utilized and maintained by Uptrends are subject to compromise. Accordingly, we cannot be held responsible for unauthorized or unintended access that is beyond our control.

## Retention of your personal data

We apply a general rule of keeping personal data only for as long as required to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected. However, in some circumstances, we may retain personal data for other periods of time, for instance where we are required to do so in accordance with legal, tax, and accounting requirements or if required to do so by a legal process, legal authority, or other governmental entity having authority to make the request for so long as required.

In specific circumstances, we may also retain your personal data for longer periods of time corresponding to a statute of limitation so that we have an accurate record of your dealings with us in the event of any complaints or challenges.

## External links

The Sites may contain links to third-party sites. Since Uptrends does not control nor is responsible for the privacy practices of those websites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third-party sites. This Policy applies solely to personal data collected by our Sites or in the course of our business activities.

## Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our website that may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email before posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed, please contact us.

## Access and data subject rights

Individuals have the right to access the personal data processed about them subject to applicable law; individuals may request to access their personal data processed by us by contacting us.

Subject to applicable law, you may also have some or all of the following rights available to you in respect of your personal data

  * to obtain a copy of your personal data together with information about how and on what basis that personal data is processed;
  * to rectify inaccurate personal data (including the right to have incomplete personal data completed);
  * to erase your personal data (in limited circumstances, such as where it is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or processed);
  * to restrict processing of your personal data under certain circumstances;
  * to port your data in a machine-readable format to a third party (or to you) when we justify our processing on the basis of your consent or the performance of a contract with you;
  * to withdraw your consent to our processing of your personal data (where that processing is based on your consent); and
  * to obtain, or see a copy of the appropriate safeguards under which your personal data is transferred to a third country or international organization.

In addition to the above rights, under EU data protection law, applicable individuals have the right to object, on grounds relating to your particular situation, at any time to any processing of your personal data for which we have justified on the basis of a legitimate interest, including profiling (as opposed to your consent) or to perform a contract with you. You also have the right to object at any time to any processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes including profiling for marketing purposes.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority for data protection.

In relation to all of these rights, please contact us at https://www.uptrends.com/contact. Please note that we may request proof of identity, and we reserve the right to charge a fee where permitted by law especially if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. We will endeavor to respond to your request within all applicable timeframes.

If you contact us regarding Customer Data for which we are a data processor, we will attempt to refer your request to the relevant Customer and data controller for your personal data.

## Signing a DPA

We are dedicated to helping our customers become GDPR compliant as well. When signing up for a subscription with Uptrends, the processing of your personal data is regulated by our Privacy Policy document. Our Privacy Policy provides you with all the necessary information on how your personal data is being processed and what exact information we process at Uptrends.

However, if you reside in the EU or your country’s law requires it from you, you can sign a  **Data Processing Agreement**  with us. To do that, contact us, and we will provide you with a DPA that you’ll be able to both review and sign.

## Contact Information

If you have any questions in relation to this Notice, please contact us by visiting https://www.uptrends.com/contact.

_This Privacy Policy was last revised on June 1, 2018._
